Jose Oliver Benitez

Portfolio joliver017.github.io/Portfolio <u>LinkedIn</u> linkedin.com/in/jose-oliver-benitez (512) 657-4490 | jose.oliver.benitez@gmail.com

Graduate of Rice University and the UT Austin Coding Boot Camp. Skills in HTML, CSS, JSON, Javascript, Ruby. Recognized as an adept technical resource with expertise understanding business requirements, identifying customer pain points, and implementing solutions that provide business value.

EXPERIENCE

Solutions Engineer - Wheel 2021 - present

- Drive technical conversations with prospects to explain the product, API, and requirements.
- **Draft technical** sections in SOWs detailing tasks to be completed for successful implementations, including flow diagrams.
- *Create sandbox & prod environments including generating API keys, environment configuration, and workflows.
- *Conduct testing during sandbox and production build phases to ensure passing of test cases and verifying successful logs.
- *Troubleshoot issues after clients are live, using FullStory, Looker, and Datadog to investigate issues.
- *Collaborate cross-functionally across multiple teams in the organization to troubleshoot variety of issues affecting integrations or operations (i.e., sales, implementation, support).

Sr. Automation Engineer - Cloudsnap 2019 - 2021

- **Code functions** using Ruby to parse, generate, calculate and format JSON data tailored to client's needs.
- Build workflows for client's data integration needs between different SaaS and ERP's (SAP Concur, NetSuite, Business Central, WorkDay, ADP, etc.)
- 'Analyze database diagrams/documentation and gain knowledge in API protocols and table relationships to ensure successful solutions installation, integration, and deployment.
- Discover and advise customer's business practices with new approaches to ensure a smooth and proper integration by uncovering potential issues.
- *Troubleshoot and resolve platform, API, and failing workflow issues.
- **Technical consultant** for enterprise customers ensuring technical integrity and high quality project delivery.

Investigations Specialist - Accenture via BC Forward 2018 - 2019

- *Conduct deep-level investigations for malicious activity within client's social media platform.
- **Lead training** sessions for new team members.
- **Identify and capture** new patterns of malicious behavior used to circumvent the platform's policy.
- **Generate and relay** feedback for improving team tools and productivity.
- **Serve as reliable** source of information to coworkers concerning policy and procedure.

EDUCATION

University of Texas, Austin, TX Coding Boot Camp 2018 - 2019

Rice University, Houston, TX

BA in Psychology 2011 - 2015 GPA: 3.79

DEVELOPMENT SKILLS

Languages/Front-End

Javascript, JSON, HTML5

CSS (BootStrap, UI-Kit)

Back-End/Databases

Ruby, Node.js

MySQL, MongoDB

GENERAL SKILLS

Spanish (Fluent)

Teamwork

Typing (100 wpm)

Fast-learner

Editina

Flexible